Well, according to my watch, we have
6:00
and I'll call the the May 4th, 2026
meeting of the Cheyenne City Planning
Commission to order.
Um,
first item of business, uh, approval of
agenda and minutes. Is there a
modification to our agenda?
>> Mr. Chair, we still need to do roll
call.
>> Oh, I guess we Yes, that's right. Roll
call first.
Staff, please call roll.
>> Bob Mati,
>> here.
>> Justin Trip,
Daryl Hibbons
>> here. Megan Connor
>> present remotely.
>> Tony Lair
>> here.
>> Amy Hernandez
>> present via Zoom.
>> Boyd Wigum
>> present.
>> Mr. Chair, we do have a quorum. And real
quick, we do have a new planning
commission member. So, welcome to
Justin. He is uh replacing Lonnie.
Okay, thank you.
Um, approval of minutes.
>> Move to approve.
>> I have a motion. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
>> Okay, we've got a motion and a second on
the table. Is there any comment or
revision
requested
from the commission? Hearing
none.
All in favor of approving the minutes
for the April 6, 2026 planning
commission meeting, please say I.
>> I.
>> Oppos.
>> Opposed. Say nay.
Motion carries.
Disclosures. Any exparte communications
conflicts of interest on any items?
by members of the commission.
Hearing none,
will staff please read item A into
the record?
Item A, PLTA-26-1,
special use approvals, creation of uh
the regulation or regional
entertainment overlay and development
standards for offtrack betting
facilities text amendment.
Okay. Can we please have a staff report?
Chair, members of the planning
commission, Charles Bloom, planning and
development director. Um, we are
requesting postponement to the midmon
meeting which will be May 18th. At that
time, we will have two text amendments
that we will be considering. One of
those being the historic horse racing
amendments as well as carports.
Um, traditionally the midmon meeting is
usually reserved for staff initiated
actions, ones that are initiated by the
metropolitan planning organization as
well as long range planning items. So,
it really will fall directly into place
during that meeting. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Questions
for the commission?
Can I have a motion?
I move to approve or to postpone this
item to the May 18th, 2026 meeting.
>> I have a second.
>> Second.
>> Have it's been moved and seconded. Any
discussion by the commission?
Will staff please call roll?
>> Tony Lair.
Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez. Hi.
Megan Connor.
>> Hi.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Hi.
>> Justin Trip.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Staff, please read item B into the
record.
Item B, PUDC-26-29/30,
Cheyenne Business Park and Camptool
Business Park zoning map amendment.
>> Okay.
Can I please have I guess it's going to
be the staff report as the applicant?
>> Yes. Uh, Mr. Chair, uh, members of the
commission, Conor Way, Planning and
Development Department. So, this is a
staff initiated zoning map amendment. um
haven't had one of these come before
you. Uh this is one of the first ones
that we are doing um in a while. I guess
actually now thinking back there was one
that we have done before. Um but this is
a larger kind of scale one. So this is
looking at camp stool and Cheyenne
Business Park over on the east side of
town along IEA.
Um, currently most of the area is either
zoned li or community business.
Uh, in the area that we're looking at,
uh, changing to business park and then
on the future land use map, most of the
area is either industrial or mixeduse
employment. There is a Public zone in
there that is the city's um, I believe
it's city water treatment plan out
there. Um,
but that would be the only one that's
that's public that's within this uh in
the future land use map.
So, what we're looking at is now that
we've got the business park zone, um, we
have been looking at trying to get these
business parks into
that zone district.
um business park zone district was
created to be basically a combination of
the hili and CB zone with some
modifications
um to it. There is different setbacks,
couple different uses does allow for
uh more uses in some cases but then also
kind of prohibits other uses that were
allowed in the hi
with this area. Uh we've had several
property owners who wanted to zone to
business park. Um they weren't able to
zone to business park on their own.
Reason for that is the business park
zone does require 320 acres uh to go to
that zone district.
Also, you have to basically so you're
not just creating spot zones. You kind
of have to have that contiguity where
that zone district kind of meshed and
moved and touched each other. So with
the property owners that wanted to go to
BP, you didn't have all those kind of
the connections or the acreage.
So uh leadeds did did ask staff if we
could look into maybe doing a city
initiated resoning. Um
when we looked at the area, we did take
what is the Cheyenne business park, took
all the properties within that and added
it to this resoning. And then we also
looked at Camp Stool Business Park
because that is also a business park and
we've actually had several lots within
Camp Stool that have actually come
before the commission where they've gone
from LI to CB and then maybe CB back to
LI or HI to LI or just kind of moving
back and forth between zone districts.
So with the BP zone, it does give more
flexibility, allows more uses um
and then
kind of allows this to develop more as
the business park that uh our zone
district kind of looks at.
With this, we did mail notice to all
property owners. So they did receal
receive mail notice. Um, I have had
several property owners that have called
and asked questions. Um, kind of just
asking what the difference is, what this
means for their property, what it means
for their uses.
Um,
I will have on the
last slide. Uh, there is a modification
that we will propose because in front of
you, you should all have a letter. Uh,
there was one property owner that did
want to be removed from the zone change.
Um
staff has no issue with removing them
from the zone change if they don't want
to be in it. It will leave them as hi.
They are on the far
um
east side.
Be kind of hard to point out exactly
where
uh but it's the old Blue Cross RV kind
of next to Camping World over there
that'd like to be left in HI. Um again,
staff has no issue with that. if any
property owner wanted to be removed, we
would probably ask planning commission
or council to remove them before this
got approved. Um, as long as we aren't
creating kind of pockets of BP moving
forward, which this does not. And then
if anybody who did get removed wants to
be in the BP later, they can come back
in and request it. Anybody who gets
zoned to BP, if they want to be out of
it, they can always come back and
request to be out of it.
So, with this area, um, it's already
built as industrial. It's already a
business park. It's why the business
park zone district was created. Staff
does recommend approval of this with
that one modification
to remove uh those lots from this
resoning.
And I do stand for any questions.
>> Okay. Thank you. Any questions for staff
from the commission?
Uh, Commissioner Lair,
>> chair through you. Connor, do you know
why uh this particular
parcel owner would rather stay
heavy industrial? Is there some use they
have in mind that's not allowed in the
business park?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Yes. So,
my understanding is they are looking to
potentially sell the property. They feel
that with the hi zone um they might have
better opportunities because it does
allow for outdoor storage. The BP
prohibits full outdoor storage. It does
allow for limited so 50% of your lot to
have outdoor storage. Anybody who has
currently existing outdoor storage in
right now on their property in use, they
do get grandfathered in. Uh they can
expand it with conditional use and
things like that. But if somebody was to
do a change of use from a property that
has no outdoor storage or isn't defined
as full 100% outdoor storage, they would
be basically they would be prohibited
from doing so. Um, basically with this
property, that's kind of their
preference. They'd like to stay in the
hi because they believe that they might
have better value and able to sell to
somebody looking to do outdoor storage
there. Um, so that's why they've
requested it. Again, staff has no issue
with the request. Um,
this was staff initiated. So with a
business park area like this, HI still
fits the area. Uh, staff feels that BP
would be better for it because again, as
I mentioned, with all the switches back
and forth for multiple different
properties, but
yeah, if somebody wanted to stick with
the zoning they had, then we would just
request that they be removed.
Any further questions of staff from
commissioners?
>> I I have one chairman for you.
>> Oh, go ahead.
>> Well, I'm gonna I'm going to yield to
Zoom land first.
Uh
>> Oh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um this is
Megan online. Um, I'm just curious if if
some of these parcel owners band
together and and sell if they're trying
to put I don't know, they're putting all
these data centers everywhere, which is
a really big concern actually. What
happens to the other property owners
that that can just happen without them
having any say under this business park
zoning? Is that correct, Connor?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So data centers
are already allowed in the LIHI zone
districts. So this doesn't change the
allowed use for data centers. So if
somebody wanted I mean there's already
data centers in this business park um in
this area that are already developing.
So the BP zone does not change the fact
that they could already do that.
>> But because of the way it's kind of I'm
just looking at a map. the way it's kind
of got different zonings in there right
now, it probably would
require at least some more notice and
going through a public process to do
that. Would would you think is that
fair,
>> Mr. Chair? Not necessarily. Um, if you
take several of the HI parcels and they
wanted to combine them into one, that'd
be an administrative plat and then an
administrative site plan. Again, the
zone districts in this area already
allow for data centers as a use by
right. Any
further questions?
I believe Commissioner Trip.
Yes, thank you through you, Chairman. Uh
Connor, you mentioned that uh some of
the business owners who want this had a
lot of reasons. What are some of the
reasons they want this to happen?
>> So, Mr. chair uh through you. Um
again the flexibility of the zone
district to allow uses
uh also it does have a reduction in
setbacks from what the hi would have. It
does have a reduced landscaping
requirements.
Um those are probably the biggest
reasons that we've heard. Uh setbackwise
in the hi I believe it is 40 foot
setbacks from all property lines. The BP
does reduce that down to, I believe, 25
on your front, maybe 25 in the rear.
I'm going off of what I'm remembering
with the BP. I know internal setbacks
are about 10 or something along those
lines. If it's next to a different zone
district than the BP, they're a little
bit bigger. So,
most of it, from what I'm hearing
though, I think is it comes down to
flexibility, landscaping, and setbacks.
>> Thank you.
Any further questions of staff from
commission?
Okay, with that,
um, I'll open this up for public
hearing.
Are there any members of the public pre
present who wish to comment?
Please provide your name and address,
sir.
Good evening, commissioners. My name is
Dante Rush and I am the director of real
estate and property management for
Cheyenne Leads, address 121 West 15th
Street, Sweet 304. I just wanted to
approach the podium and show our support
for this zoning map amendment to the BP
zoning. Uh we appreciate working with
staff as they've put together a staff
report and the recommendations. And uh
what I've also have if if it's allowed
to provide is just a comparative
analysis table showing the BP zoning to
the different zoning districts already
in Cheyenne Business Parkway just to
show the benefits of more allowed uses
by right landscaping requirements and
then the different setback requirements
that uh Mr. White had alluded to. So BP
is a a great economic tool that we can
use to help speed projects to market by
allowing more uses allowed by right. But
that is the nature of my comments. I'm
open for any questions.
Thank you.
Um anybody else from the public wish to
comment on this item?
Is there anybody in Zoom land?
>> And for those on Zoom, you will need to
use the raise hand feature tonight. If
you do have any comments on any items.
>> Nothing from Zoom.
>> Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is closed.
I'm looking for a motion from
commission.
I move to recommend the governing body
approve the resoning of Cheyenne
Business Park and Camp Comptool Business
Park to BP Business Park as shown in the
attached zone change map, noting that
the project meets the review required
review criteria for approval of the
following modifications. One, removal of
lots and two block one stool RV edition.
and two, removal of lots three and four,
block three, camp stool edition fourth
filing.
>> Okay. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
>> Okay. It's been moved and seconded.
Um any discussion by the commission,
comments, concerns,
proposed amendments
hearing? None.
Staff please call roll.
Justin Trip.
>> Yay.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> I
>> Tony Lair.
>> I. Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
Okay, thank you.
Staff read, please read item C into the
record.
>> Item C, PUDC-26-50,
Harmony Valley 23rd filing expedited
plat.
>> Okay. Do I have an applicant?
Good evening. John Sers, agent for
Trigger Land Development.
Before we bringing you tonight a 196 lot
subdivision, you guys approved the zone
change March 2nd on this. This was a
continuation of the Harmony Valley fifth
filing. Um what was discussed back in
the zone change can even be further uh
addressed at this time period. This is
the exact similar product that we're
building, getting ready to build where
we're doing attached garages
and making single family homes. So that
way the common walls between the garages
and not the actual physical units where
the living quarters are in in this
particular situation
with that um there is open space. We
provided tonight a copy of the green and
then how the open space works. The open
space is what makes the block length
slightly bigger in between a couple of
the blocks. Hence the reason why we went
ahead and just asked for that and pushed
that through. I know that there was some
concern questions asking about how we
were getting people in and around. Um
you can see that we do have a trail
network, but we also have the greenway
pathway running up Grand Harmony
Boulevard from Center One or the
apartment complex to the south. It runs
all the way up to Allison. Uh we are
working with city engineering staff for
a connection potentially over at Melody
Loop only for pedestrian but due to a
15% slope at that point making ADA
requirements might not be financially
possible at this point. That would still
give that adjacent subdivision access to
go ahead and come around at center one
or as they continue to keep doing
climbing over the hill anyways
potentially and going up and trespassing
on the land. as you can see from the
trail marks of where they've been
walking on the said lane. With that
said, we have been working with the
school district recently um in lowering
and and sloping the hill out so that way
it's a more manageable hill for them and
for us. With that said, they have no
direct access to the school off the
south side completely. It is fenced off.
Every bit of it is fenced off. So, the
access would be going up Grand Avenue or
Grand Harmony Boulevard all the way to
Allison or they'll cut across until we
have homes there up at the top side. Um,
also, it's worth noting that York will
be extended to Cribbon. That is a 2028
program change uh to get that put on and
get that completed.
Believe I've addressed any questions.
I'm happy to stand and answer any if you
have any.
Are there any questions for the
applicant from the commission? Uh,
Commissioner Leard
chair through you. This uh you mentioned
the last thing you mentioned the York
being extended to Cribbon. So, is that a
city street project they're proposed for
2028?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Yes, sir. That
is completely their project at that
point. They've been working with us and
the school district for the platting
capabilities to go ahead and remove some
easements that are on South High School.
Uh, we actually have rights to those
easements. We're working on that, but
it's contingent upon a BOP issue. So, I
can't release those exactly at this
moment, but we are working with staff to
get that taken care of. So, that way we
still have access should we need to make
a water connection, but the road is
supposed to be extended as you can see
on the monitors and that does take you
up the hill and get you to that point.
So we actually just completed this past
week the storm inlets at the bottom of
the hill at York and Caroland. So that
way any water that does come down that
hill gets collected at that point and
goes down to our pond at the park which
we use the recycled water to water the
fields and such.
Uh, additional questions. Commissioner
Trip Trip
>> Chairman threw you. Uh, I'm not sure if
you have the answer for this, but I'm
curious. Water is a big resource up here
and adding 196 lots up there. What is
the water usage going to be and what
effect is that going to have as we're in
water restrictions and other things
right now?
>> Mr. Chair, through you BOP probably can
address this a little bit easier, but
the water restrictions are not that
situation for the residential areas. So,
um, we've been working with them since
Harmony Valley first filing through the
fifth filing and now all the way to what
is the 23rd and we have the 24th in
already. So, that'll be coming forward
here shortly anyway. So, that's about
the amount of changes. Um, currently
that subdivision is fed with uh
two connections. BOP is asking for a
third connection. Um that connection may
come in over off of College and Parsley
off of the other line or as discussed
slightly beforehand uh with South High
there's a fire hydrant on the far east
side of that that we could tap into but
there is no water pressure drop over
there. Actually EOP's water pressure in
that area is better than South Cheyenne
water and sewer districts water pressure
if that addresses your question. Thank
you.
Any other questions of the applicant?
Are there any questions?
>> This is Megan.
>> Yes, Commissioner.
>> I did have a question. I I remember this
one coming through. I just wanted to
confirm that this outside of York and
Grand Harmony, they this was not going
to link with the other two subdivisions
that were right there to the east and
west. Is that correct?
Uh, Commissioner uh Connor, could you
please restate your question? I'm
getting quizzical looks from the
applicant. I was trying to follow the
question as well.
>> Okay, so they want 196 lots. I'm
guessing the only exit out of this
portion of the subdivision is Allison
and Grand Harmony to College.
They couldn't cut through the other two
neighborhoods if people are trying to
exit this subdivision.
Okay,
>> Mr. Chair, through you, if I can to to
answer that question, no, there's
actually four accesses to this
subdivision. U you do have the Allison
connection, which is a collector. You
have Grand Harmony to the southeast
corner there. You'll notice that York
along what would be the southwesterly
side of the subdivision already exists
as the previous Harmony Valley fifth
filing there is attached. So Danny Place
goes from York all the way to Carolanne
as a relief as does Carolan Way on the
high side all the way to Grand Harmony
as well. Those roads York actually dumps
straight out onto College or you can
take uh Carolan down to Richard Martin
and go out LCG road. So no we we did
connect to the existing Harmony Valley.
The problem with the subdivision to the
east is Melody Lane or Melody Loop. And
again, there is no way to get 15%
slope to get our road to connect to the
existing road at that point.
>> Okay. And I I was wondering about the
same uh
>> I think you're next.
>> Chair, members of the planning
commission, Charles Bloom playing the
bow director. I just want to note that
this is a final plat. So the purpose of
a final plat is to review its compliance
with the preliminary plat. Well, it is
an expedited plat.
All right, I'm going to go back a little
bit. So in 2019 when we first considered
this plan unit development and the
related subdivision, there's a lot of
discussion regarding access and uh
different agreements were made between
the developer and the city um and the
school district as well because they
have South High School mainly to the
north. Um as part of this, the city had
worked with the developer because we
will be providing the extension of York
Street to the north. um that is
presently in a little bit of design
right now. But this specific connection
to Harmony Meadows, which is immediately
to the east, um that was specifically
discussed in a lot of detail. Um as Mr.
Sars did note, there is a pretty
significant um elevation change between
the end of that stub street and the
subdivision. that results in a grade
that is very unfavorable for a street
connection because it almost doubles the
allowable street percentage for a grade
to go up. A lot of the reasons for that
is because of a high um a high voltage
transmission line that runs along the
eastern boundary of the subdivision
which made it very problematic to do any
extensive grading that would remedy
that. Unfortunately, that is a result of
of issues we had with previous platting
where those stubs were provided
unfortunately in areas where they just
couldn't be reasonably accommodated. So,
they're they're trying to make their
best efforts at providing that
pedestrian connection at this time,
which hopefully they can figure out way
to do that within um their their price
point.
So, I just I just want to note that um
as we do have several newer uh members
that may not be aware of the history on
this really what we're we're looking at
is comparing this to the plan unit
development and the previous plats even
though this is significantly revised um
to note that it still follows uh what
was envisioned with that and what was
previously approved.
>> Okay,
>> Mr. Chairman, I just had a comment on
that because I was I was there when we
moved this this lot out of the PUD and
my only comment is that they said that
traffic wasn't a problem and that it had
been closed, but you know, my grandma
lives over there. I was there on Sunday
afternoon just just yesterday. It was a
disaster. It like it was going down
College Drive. There were people just
whipping in and out already up those
roads. That's why I asked. So, I guess
my concern is definitely the the traffic
on college and where that's going to go,
how they're going to handle that in that
particular area.
>> Okay. And it it sounds to me like uh
would you please address address the
question about uh traffic traffic
studies? What's going to happen off site
as a result of this increase demand?
>> Mr. chair through you. I think one of
the things that um is kind of comes into
play in this particular question is two
parts. One is is you have two major
arterial roads to the north of us and to
the south of us. They are designed to
move traffic. I can tell you that the
speed limit up to Triumph on the south
of College from the elementary or
Walters actually from South Gley all the
way to Grand Harmony Boulevard is 30 m
an hour. I can also tell you that people
do not obey the traffic law speed limit
in that area. The traffic speed
increases from Grand Harmony Boulevard
up to York to 40 miles an hour. Um
that's one of the reasons there will be
a deceleration lane being put in as part
of theou that was previously done on the
Harmony Valley fifth filing. Secondly,
as soon as you get to midway between
York and LCG, the speed limit increases
to 50 mph through that stretch. So
whether sheriff's department or highway
patrol wants to go out and and slow down
traffic, that's outside of our
parameters. Uh the traffic study that
has been submitted does show that the
access off that to get people inside the
neighborhood to those two major roadways
is more than adequate for the design of
how this was laid out. As we've gone
through the process,
there is no other accesses as well
except for the York going all the way up
to Cribbon, which will dump you in on
the high side on the far west. So, we
are taking care of the critical design
to get a traffic moving through the
area. We are not pushing traffic through
Harmony Meadows, but there is an option
for people should they choose to do
that. And there is it's just like
anybody going through any subdivision.
somebody can go through Harmony Meadows,
come down around on the bottom side and
get to uh center one and wrap around on
the bottom side, which is the access to
the elementary on the back side and the
apartments there. So, we we have taken
pretty good caution to make sure which
roads we want to push through and which
ones we can't um to slow down the
traffic to the best of our ability. But,
Grand Harmony is designed to move
traffic between the two collectors at
that point for mining materials.
Okay.
>> Okay. And and speaking of traffic,
I guess predictably, I want to ask a
little bit about pedestrian traffic. You
mentioned how South High School is
completely fenced.
We can see on the map that there's a
foot path that would appear to go
through that fence.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. I will address
that. you can easily go out and look.
That fence carries along the south side
of the school. As it starts to run up
the east side, once it gets to the
parking lot of South High, the fence
cuts back towards the school at that
point. So, that is their own security
fence. The other question you might
raise, and it's easily addressed as
well, is Triumph just started with Alco
because of the board gave them funding
to go ahead and fence that completely
off. So the idea that people crisscross
through these schools is no longer the
capability and there is no gates on the
south high school side that gets you in
except for near the tennis courts that
allows for Larry County School
District's one's vehicles to get in and
do maintenance on the top side.
I'd just like to and and did we have
well I guess we'll ask staff about
communications with the school district.
Personally, I like the idea of of
pedestrian access from a neighborhood to
the adjacent school. Was there ever any
conversation or contemplation of the
plat to provide for a way to get to the
point where
you know where the edge of that security
fence is to accommodate that traffic or
>> so Mr. Chair through you if I may I can
understand and respect the idea that
you're trying to get access closer and
more diagonal to the school. We're
installing the greenway pathway along
college or Grand Harmony along the whole
west side of this to go up and then you
have the same greenway pathway running
along York to go up to Cribbon which is
the two points of where you really want
individuals to go through versus just
climbing up a hill and going through up
that angle. So, we have lessened the
angle, but prior to working with the
school district, you would have had a 12
to 16 foot wall on the bottom side of
our property. We've eliminated that
capabilities by working with the school
district to get the slope down.
To further address it, I can ask this,
how many accesses should we be granting
to get to that point? But also, we're
giving the greenway pathway and and all
the sidewalks to get there. So, we're
just trying to, as you can see, they've
been trespassing for years. So, we have
to be very cautious when we're out
running equipment. Even though we sit
out there, we park vehicles at times to
tell them to please go around.
They could walk around on Allison on the
greenway pathway up there on the south
side of Allison all the way around the
corner and come down Walterside and get
back into Harmony Meadows.
So
from a standpoint of making sure there's
access, I think we've over provided
access other than a straight going to
the fence that doesn't allow you to get
into the back of South.
>> Okay. Any other questions from the
commission? Commissioner Leair.
>> Mr. Chair, you have a couple questions.
So one is follow up on the road system.
What are the what's the functional
classification of Grand Harmony and
York? Are they local roads or
collectors?
>> Mr. Chair, through you I am going to
tell you I believe those are local
streets going through at that point to
get to the two major roadways.
This might be a better question when
staff's turn, but uh have you have you
heard if the city I mean obviously I'm
hearing from Commissioner Connor about
problems with uh access or congestion
getting from this these areas into
college. Have they looked at uh I'm sure
they're looking at signals either there
or perhaps up at Parsley. Have you heard
this?
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, if I can through you on
that particular one instead of Cotter
Wat has full intentions of expanding
college drive through that area. We've
actually in the Harmony Valley first
filing had strips of land that we
platted so that when and if they choose
to widen College through that area that
they have the land to do that. We are
not clear on that timeline, but as
everything keeps developing south,
especially south of College Drive at
this point, I do see that moving up in
in the forecast for um Y dot to actually
expand the road.
>> Mr. Chair, the the other unrelated
question again back to pedestrians and
the melody loop thing. I guess I need to
clarify. I understand the grade is
steep. So, it would be perhaps
impossible or not feasible to make a a
proper path connection that meets ADA
standards. And then the applicant
mentioned
the existing trail is trespassing, if
you will. Um, is it possible to grant an
to just plat an easement across there
without constructing anything? So, at
least the trail probably would continue
to be used but not be a trespass.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. I guess I'm
confused. Are you asking for us to put
another access up to south from
Difference of Grand Harmony on one of
the old trails that we plan on
potentially putting lots on as as we
move forward? Because if we if we have
to put an easement in, at that point you
have a situation where we cannot vacate
an easement until you go ahead and
replat. And personally, having an
easement just for pedestrian access to
get across puts us in a liability
situation for them to trespass on our
land. So I don't know that I would feel
comfortable saying that now I'm granting
an access easement that I can be sued
for because of pedestrian access once we
go ahead and we get Grand Harmony up and
York up. I'm I'm I'm a little confused
by that.
>> Yeah, I wasn't necessarily even thinking
about access to South High School. Just
kind of some interconnectivity for
pedestrians who might be say walking
through those neighborhoods um
exercising, walking their dogs, doing
things like that. Just give make another
connection between one fairly big
subdivision to another. Uh I I'm
familiar I live kind of northeast part
of town near Mustang Ridge and there
there's an easement there that I
actually walk across with my dog uh from
a Mustang Ridge Street kind of between
two lots that connects into a gravel
road called Tranquility by the water
tanks and I I I don't I don't know but
it it seems like a similar situation.
There's just a foot path across the
grass, but if you look at the plat, it's
uh there's an easement across there.
>> Mr. Chair, if I can. So, we are trying
our best at at Melody Loop. That is the
only connection that those residents
have a capability of coming across.
There is no other access points because
of property ownership at that point. We
met with uh city engineer Tom Cobb a
week ago or so on that. And the and the
question really comes in is that when
you look at that connection whether or
not that has to be ADA or not. If that
is an ADA requirement, we are looking at
a substantial zipper effect to carry the
grade to get the 8% to get to a landing
spot and so forth plus retaining walls.
It becomes a maintenance issue of who's
responsible for the maintenance of what
could be graffiti or or damage to those
walls. So we are trying to take a look
at that at that point. We know that the
kids do come all the way down to the
apartment complex on the south side
there because some are living there.
Some cut through our Grand Harmony
complex down to the south of us there
instead of using the sidewalk. But we
also watch the pattern as they come
around the corner at center one and go
back into the subdivision. And then
there are the ones that actually walk
along Allison and come south on
Walterite. So we do see both. We see all
those patterns on a daily basis. Any
other questions of the applicant?
Will staff please report uh read your
report into the record?
Members of commission counterweight
planning and development department.
So the application before you it's for
an expedite plat for roughly 49.56 acres
of land. The plat does propose creating
196 lots. Uh they do have 12 open space
lots within their uh within this
proposed subdivision.
Uh this proposed development is similar
to Harmony Valley Fifth Filing
uh which is just to the west
and it would be developed in a cottage
lot style um per the UDC.
So property on the future land use map
it is urban residential with a small
portion being uh mixed use residential I
believe and then the zoning for the
property uh the zone change to NR3 has
been approved by the governing body. So
the full property is actually zoned NR3.
As I mentioned, the proposed plat does
match uh what was originally or
previously approved with Harmony Valley
Fifth. So, it does continue green space
um kind of open space trails does have
alleys. Again, this is going to be
developed with cottage lots uh per the
UDC, which requires reloaded access. Um
and also having the front doors face
open space on a majority of the lots.
does allow for front doors to face
streets but doesn't allow front loading
which is also something the NR3 doesn't
allow but the codel lot section of code
does also allow for reduced lot sizes.
They are proposing to continue their um
open space network with trails as well
as additional kind of off- streetet
parking areas uh throughout the
neighborhood.
This plat does link as mentioned by the
applicant um West Allison down to
College using Grand Harmony Boulevard
and then does link over to York and the
rest of Harmony Valley.
The applicant did provide a um drainage
study and that was reviewed and uh the
engineering department had no concerns.
a transportation study uh was submitted
and reviewed with Harmony Valley fifth
filing which did take into account this
filing as well. Uh so with this filing a
traffic impact letter was submitted and
there were no concerns with the original
study and the traffic impact letter.
All these lots do uh do meet the cottage
lot section of code. Uh with cottage
lots, there will be site plans required
for the subdivision for the uh the open
space.
Uh when I came to the question about the
school district, the school district
made no comments on the plat.
Um
I don't I don't know exactly what the
school district would say, but even if
we had a sidewalk that went directly to
the property line, it doesn't mean the
school district is going to have to
provide any connection to that sidewalk,
and it may not be a sidewalk that they
want to have. Um,
as was mentioned, there is the city
project to connect Gribbin to York. Uh,
I do actually have that slide. I did
have it up earlier. So, that is
currently being uh engineered and worked
on. And then a plat will probably be
coming before planning commission in a
couple months uh when that plat is ready
to move forward.
based on meeting all the review
criteria. Staff does recommend approval
um
with a with a condition and an
exception. That exception is to block
size. Uh as was mentioned by the
applicant, these are larger blocks, but
they are broken up by green space. We
have had this in the past where when you
do cottage lot style development, uh the
blocks tend to be a little bit bigger
because you are required to have that
green space, but it does break up the
block because it runs directly through
um each block and makes a pedestrian
connection.
So staff does recommend that exception.
And then the condition. Um, as was
mentioned, the applicant is working with
the engineering department on the
potential pedestrian connection to
Melody Loop.
So
based on that, we do not have an
easement currently on the plat uh
because they don't know exactly what
that connection is going to look like or
even if it is feasible. So the condition
that staff recommends is that a
pedestrian access easement be provided
connecting Melody Loop to Grand Harmony
Boulevard. If the ex um if after
extensive engineering
uh the city engineer determines the
pedestrian connection is not feasible,
the director may wave or modify this
condition. So that doesn't tie them up
completely. Um it basically if it does
come down to where it just isn't
feasible um it isn't going to work then
uh director Bloom could wave that um
basically that condition. So that
doesn't tie up the plaque completely
with a condition that says you have to
have uh that pedestrian easement. Um but
the applicant is working on that and
would provide it if any if uh if access
can be uh basically granted.
So again, staff does recommend approval
with the conditions and the exceptions.
Well, condition and exception, and I am
available for any questions.
Connor,
what can we do to force the school
district to show up and talk about
preventing pedestrian access for
students to schools?
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, I don't believe we can
force the school district to do
anything.
Okay, commissioners
questions for staff.
>> Mr. Chair, I would like to add they do
have a review on these plats. Um, on
most projects, they have no comments.
>> I realize that
Mr. chair through you a couple of
comments but wanted just a general
comment on that question about the
school district that I I know there's an
exercise from time to time because I
think it took place this past year where
they look at the safe routes to schools
plan and it's and I know there's city
people involved obviously the school
district's involved I think white dot
provides federal funding to help support
that kind of planning and I I I see a a
big map come out with bullets and
they've got little spot projects that
are prioritized near many of the schools
around the city. So, I I would say at
least there's some opportunity in that
which isn't during the platting of a
subdivision, but at least it's a kind of
an ongoing operational review uh perhaps
to people to get input. Um
my my little technical question here,
maybe you can put that uh York to
Cribbon connection back up again. What's
that cross street that it's tying into
the east west? Is that Pinto?
Okay, that's what I wondered. Thank you.
>> Any other questions of staff from the
commission?
Chair through you. Aaron Gates, city
staff engineer. Yes, the connection to
the west is Pinto, north is Carribon.
Uh, and if you see there's actually a
sidewalk that goes down behind some of
those existing residences and ties down
in. And I'm not sure what the further
culde-sac is, but that connection will
be made there. Just so you know, these
are about 90% plans. Um, so they're not
finalized. And the reason they're not
final is due to um a deed that needs to
be transferred and some work like that.
So part of this is the cleanup of the
survey. There's a number of easements
that need to be extinguished and cleaned
up in this area. Um, you can see there
is a 10-foot greenway on the north side
of York here that will provide that
connection up toward Cribbon. So, bigger
picture for the entire neighborhood in
this entire area.
And as mentioned previously, this is
programmed for 2028, but that may be
pushed due to other priorities with city
engineering staff.
And then there was a question previously
about the uh classification of York and
Grand Harmony. They are currently minor
collectors as well as Pinto and
Carribon. And so the other streets then
would be local streets.
Thank you.
Are there any comments or questions from
our commissioners attending via Zoom?
Hearing
none. Any other questions from
commissioner here? Commissioner here.
With that,
Commissioner Lar.
>> Well, I've thought of one more or
another followup I started to ask the
developer about. But um again back to
the issue of traffic on college which
may not be as directly related to this
because I think they've covered what
they have to do is from a development
standpoint but um I think there was a a
corridor study several years ago on
parsley and I assume they talked about
basically the the road network and
parsley and college and uh there's an
existing signal at Waltershide.
So I guess I wondered is there any
discussion yet about other operational
improvements as this residential area
continues to add a lot of traffic into
the system
and chair through you the members of the
planning commission. Um the the Wyoming
Department of Transportation recently uh
did their own corridor study for the
College Drive corridor essentially from
I25 all the way to Interstate 80. Um
that one was done through WOT not
through our NO and they had an
engagement process and on that they had
identified a new cross-section. They
looked at traffic projections and I
believe what was identified through that
area was that the immediate need and the
need in the foreseeable future for that
roadway was what you see today.
Essentially a three-lane section, center
turn lane and the two the two travel
lanes. I will see if we can get that
document pulled um over to us so we can
get that out to you. They didn't warrant
any additional right ofway or changes.
Um there there is a plan in the future
um to uh widen that road, but it is way
down the DO's uh plan out there.
Regarding other corridor plans in the
area, we are seeing a lot of activity um
sort of just discussed in the south. Uh
one of the items we have is Parsley
Boulevard, which is presently to the
west of this development. Uh where we've
had one plan in the past that had it
going due south through an electrical
substation. There's another plan where
it kind of meanders a little bit to the
to the west and parallels Interstate 25.
Um, it's come to our attention lately
that that electrical substation will be
relocated. So, it does change the way
that that roadway uh could be developed
in the future. Right now, the
Metropolitan Organization is working
with the city and county. That's what
they do. They're doing a long range
transportation study uh with a
consultant for to evaluate potential
alignments for parsley in that area,
which will help um hopefully provide
some alternative access um in the
surrounding area. Uh that plan is not
expected to be complete for at least 12
months is my understanding. Could be a
little bit longer. Um and that plan is
exactly what it is. It's a it's a plan.
and it's a feasibility study. Um any
changes to the roadway network based on
that would have to go through a formal
comprehensive plan and a major street
plan process. Um, I do understand that
the city and
uh mostly the county are are working on
carrying out the promises from the last
six penny election for the construction
of division of Wallik which would extend
Waltershide
south uh to Wallik um towards a new
school in that direction. um with that
roadway uh development that would work
on changing again the habits of traffic
in the area. Um this area definitely
there's a lot of changes in traffic, a
lot of unpredictable items that are
coming through, but something that I
know that our engineers, our NO and the
DOT are are paying definite attention
to. I hope that answered your question.
I've got one more question I guess to
staff kind of stemming on on the issue
that that I'm brought up with the school
district and I I don't think it
necessarily affects how we handle this
proposed plat
even though I personally think what
we're doing with pedestrians here
violates especially the notion of
accessing things.
Students accessing the school by foot
violates
everything I understand to be
appropriate planning in an urban context
where where pedestrianism and and and
pedestrian access and mobility
needs to be enhanced, not cut off and
try to get people to walk the long way
around.
Is there anything we can do as we're
looking at maybe updating UDC or the
next round of of UDC updates that could
strengthen language
to try to better protect and enhance
direct pedestrian access
not only in this situation but around
around the city.
Chair, members of the planning
commission, Charles Bloom playing the
development director. Uh, great topic to
bring up with our schools. We've had a
lot of these built in the area in recent
years, including South High School,
Coyote Ridge, Metallark. One of the
constant challenges that we run into
when it comes to school funding, which
is divvied out by the state, is that
they are number one only receiving money
to fund school construction and the
minimum necessary for uh people to get
to the school at the present time. So
they are never given funding for future
thought of how people will get there in
the future when the neighborhood
develops to the south. For example, in
this area, uh if you go up York Street,
there's a the roadway, I believe it's is
that uh at not Allison, the connector
between Pinto and Allison that is
Cribbon. Cribbon is not developed
because there was no funding that was
put in place for that roadway. Uh we
have a similar issue on Carlson at
Coyote Ridge where there's a several
hundred foot gap that was not developed
because of that. that will ultimately
fall on the the city um to to develop
that. Same thing goes with pedestrian
connections. So, in this specific case,
that would have been a pedestrian
connection to nowhere and it wouldn't
qualify for major maintenance dollars
for the school district. Uh there is an
opportunity for you all to speak on
this, to talk about this, to get
involved on May 19th in Casper, Wyoming,
and you can attend via Zoom. The select
committee on school facilities will be
studying infrastructure requirements for
new school facilities as part of their
interim uh committee studies. Um that is
one that WHAM the Wyoming association
municipalities is very active in that
we've been doing a lot of research on to
try to prevent these scenarios from
happening where we have these poorly
connected schools that only serve the
immediate and present time instead of
serving what they will develop to be in
the future. So, long story short, yes,
you have an opportunity to get involved.
Um, Wham, our municipal lobbying group,
they will be involved. Um, but you all
are welcome to as planning commission
members, members of the public, you
know, on May 19th, you attend virtually
and Casper on that.
Okay. Thank you.
With that, I'll open this item up for
public comment.
Is there any member of the public here
that wants to comment on this item?
Is there any member of public the public
that is attending via Zoom that wishes
to comment on this?
Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is now closed.
I'm looking for a motion from the
commission.
Mr. Chair, I move to approve the Harmony
Valley 23rd filing preliminary plat
advancing the final plat to the
governing body with staff recommended
conditions and exceptions.
>> Second.
>> Okay, thank you. You beat me to it. It's
been moved and seconded.
uh discussion among the commission uh
comments
proposed amendments.
Mr. share through you. I just I'm in
support of the motion and I think uh I
appreciate what this developer has has
done and
uh changing to respond to the market for
these smaller, more affordable
housing, more attainable affordable
housing, which which is a big problem in
our city and in our state. And I think
this uh these recent subdivisions in
this area help meet that need. Any
other comments?
I'd like to echo what Commissioner
Larard said. I don't get to have a vote
on this. Um I I am pleased as punch with
the product and and the pivot that's
occurred. Um but just to follow up on my
previous comment and and and just the
nature of what what this this uh the
market that this is seeking is seeking
to meet. It even further concerns me
that the we appear to be powerless to
try to provide a way for people who live
in this area to get to the school. that
I'm envisioning families with kids
attending the schools in the area just
because of kind of what the product is
and and and
it strikes me as being
a market that would be more in need of
of
allowing kids to to get places by foot
and not needing an extra vehicle and the
expense associated with that and the
traffic generated with that. You know,
there's been some discussion of of you
know, what is it going to do the traffic
volumes? Well, in my mind,
preventing anything other than a long
circuitous pedestrian route to get to
the destinations that I expect people
try to get and will try to get to just
compounds whatever additional traffic
volume and congestion that's going to
flow from this. So, I think we're
working at cross purposes with the
pedestrian issue. It it frankly it
disgusts me, but I thank the developer
for and and and for thank the developer
for working to meet our previous
requests for connectivity
for traffic and automobiles and willing
to work with trying to make connection
to the development of these.
Without any other further comments or
questions,
will staff please call roll.
>> Tony Leard,
>> I Amy Hernandez,
>> I
>> Bob Mati,
>> Justin Trip,
>> I
>> Megan Connor,
>> Daryl Hibbons,
>> I.
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, the motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you.
And with that, uh, will, uh, staff
please read item D into the record.
>> Item D, PUDC-26-52,
Bolo Properties Expedited Plot. Okay.
Thank you. Do I have an applicant ready
to present?
Mr. Chair, through you John Sers's agent
for True Grit Development and CE
Investments.
I'd like to touch on one thing on in
regards to the schools just outside
um working with the school districts on
a lot of the projects that we have
worked on.
What you're not familiar with is they
are literally locking down the sites
with the fencing and there are sites
where they do not want them to have
bystanders standing out in certain areas
for kids to come by. I dealt with that
over in Saddle Ridge on the uh next
elementary school over there. And when
we were working on pathways, I know it's
irrelevant to this, but I just wanted to
touch on it. Um, it is a it is difficult
to figure out how they want that
controlled and to limit where people are
coming in on their property. So, I I can
respect what you've asked for. I I I
truly can, but I know that my kids lived
in Monterey Heights and went to Hobs and
they cross story. So, I get it. And they
walked every day. So, all right, back to
the meeting at hand. Um, this is a uh
apartment complex that we went in and
asked for a conditional use uh to go
ahead and do uh multifamily housing
directly across from Sun Valley School.
Um, there is already a pedestrian
pathway to get you across right there.
So, we have that already figured out.
With that said, we have eight lots for
eight individual ownerships of forplexes
with a ninth lot being the common and
open space maintenance issue. This is a
similar product that the bison
properties you just approved uh over on
Grand Harmony
where each individual owner has a one
and eighth interest in lot 9 that takes
care of the landscaping, the parking lot
and all the maintenance issues at that
point. Um we did gain a conditional use
approval previously. We have submitted a
site plan already that is going through
the process and moving forward with this
plat plat allows us to go ahead and find
financing for individuals that are
coming in and buying one or two of the
actual buildings not individual units
and therefore the maintenance is taken
care of through their own HOA at that
point. Happy to address any questions
you have.
>> Okay, thank you. Any questions from the
commission?
Any comm questions from commissioners on
Zoom?
Hearing? None. Staff, please read your
report into the record.
>> Mr.
Mr. Chairman, uh, members of the
commission, Morgan Dennis, Planning and
Development. Um, this is an expedited
plat for 1.42 acres of land located
south of East 12th Street, east of Crest
Park Drive.
>> Hold on. Hold on. Are you able to pick
this up because we're not hearing on
speakers. Okay.
>> Just sounds very different in here.
>> Hello.
>> There we go. Okay.
>> Do I need to like completely start over
or
Okay. Okay. Um the lot is currently
vacant.
Um the purpose of this plat is to vacate
10 lots in the culdesac and create the
common lot and individual lots for the
buildings. Um
he already hit a lot of what I was going
to say. Um parcel is currently
undergoing a site plan process with our
department. Um future land use map
designates this area as urban
residential. Um zoning is MR.
Multi-buildings are conditional use. He
got that in August of 2025.
Um, all the lot types are allowed in the
MR zone. Um, after meeting all review
criteria, staff recommends approval and
I stand for questions.
>> Okay, thank you. Any questions of staff
from the commission?
Anything from the commissioners via
attending via Zoom?
Hearing none, I will open this item up
for public comment.
Is there anybody from the public on Zoom
that wishes to speak on this?
Going once, going twice, and for the
record, there is nobody from the public
in the in the meeting.
Public comment is closed.
I am looking for a motion from the
commission.
Commissioner Hibben. Yes sir. Uh I move
to approve the
Polo Properties preliminary plat
advancing the final plat to the
governing body. Okay.
>> Thank you. Do I have a second?
>> I will second that motion.
>> Okay. It's been seconded by Commissioner
Trip. Uh comments, questions,
discussion, amendments from the
commission?
Anything from the commissioners on Zoom
hearing? None. Will staff please call
roll.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Hi
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Justin Trip.
>> Hi
>> Megan Connor.
Hi,
>> Tony Lair.
>> I Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. Will staff please read
item E into the record.
>> Item E, PUDC-26-57,
Darnell home sites second filing
expedited plot.
Thank you. Do we have an applicant who
wishes to present?
>> And Mr. Chair, our applicant is online.
I have granted them permission to speak.
>> Okay. Well, thank you,
applicant.
>> Good evening, chair, members of the
planning commission. Can you hear me?
Okay.
>> Yes.
>> Doing an audio check. Okay, great. Um,
good evening, Brandon Swain, 3201
Cheyenne Street, agent for the
applicant. I'd like to apologize that
I'm not there in person. I'm currently
out of the country. It's 2:08
a.m. right now. Um, but I already had
this travel booked before we submitted
the project. So, um, if I can just I'll
be brief. Um, this, uh, the original
site is one existing dwelling. The
property is addressed off 4320 Ridge
Road. Uh, the site is generous in size.
It has what we would call dual frontage.
So the current house fronts Ridge Road
meets appropriate setbacks. However,
there's an abundance of extra lot area
immediately west of this property that
fronts Darnell and we're essentially
proposing uh generating a total of five
lots. One lot will remain with the
existing dwelling and uh generating four
new lots that will front Darnell. Um
pretty cut and dry. Uh, BOPU has asked
us to provide an easement um in case the
existing property at 4320 Ridge, which
is currently on septic, if that fails,
um, the most reasonable way to extend
those utilities, both water and sewer,
would be to Darnell. Um, I have spoke
with VOPU. The easement that we have in
place essentially splitting the lots uh,
north and south right in the middle uh,
is sufficient. I haven't had much
controversy on this project. That being
said, I stand for any questions.
>> Okay. Thank you. Um,
for the record, Commissioner Tris Trip
has exited the meeting. Um, is there any
are there any questions of the applicant
from the commission?
Uh, Commissioner Leair, Mr. Mr. Chair,
through you and maybe this is for the
city too, but I I'm just curious uh
because Darnell is currently a gravel
road. Is that got to be upgraded, paved,
sidewalk, curb, gutter, any of that done
as part of this project?
>> Uh so if I may, I'll comment, but I did
hear um city engineer Aaron Gay in the
office, so she can absolutely correct me
if I'm wrong. Um but we we held a
meeting specific to this project before
I left town because I think it's
important not only for members of the
planning commission but my clients as
well to understand what those
expectations are. Uh where we landed is
uh the road as it's currently
constructed is too narrow. However, the
sufficient rideway is in place and we've
been asked to widen the road to
appropriate standards. Essentially, that
would mean that we're going to improve
that road and encroach it a little bit
further on the property to the east. And
then we're going to uh install curb cur,
excuse me, curbon, gutter, and sidewalk
along the east side of the property. Uh
there, excuse me, um along the frontage
of the lots on Darnell Place. There is
an existing dwelling that's sitting on
the west end of Darnell, but how they're
currently parking, we don't anticipate
any participation
um from them on improving any of the
public infrastructure. If we install
curb gutter and sidewalk and widen the
road, we're going to have an issue as
that road um abuts the current alley
approaches that are just to the north.
Uh there's ones on each side of Darnell.
Um the city has stated uh that they
would likely cooperate with us. So as
we're widening the road, installing
sidewalk curb and gutter, uh the whole
point of all that is to help facilitate
and offset drainage. And currently the
valley pan and the alley and how that's
constructed isn't conducive to that. So,
it's going to be a joint venture with
the expectation of the clients or
whoever develops the property to again
take on the cost of widening the gravel
road, installing curb cutter and
sidewalk on their property with some
participation with the city on improving
those alley approaches to the north.
Any further questions of the applicant?
Was that a sufficient explanation?
Okay. With that, will staff please
read the report into record?
>> Mr. Chair, members of the commission,
Morgan Dennis, Planning and Development.
Um, this is an expedited plat for 1.02
acres of land located at 40 4320 Ridge
Road. This lot is currently, this lot
currently has a residential structure on
half the parcel and vacant for the rest.
The purpose of this plat is to subdivide
one lot into five lots for residential
use. The future land use map designates
this area as mixeduse residential. The
zoning for this parcel is MR medium
density residential. The lots facing
Darnell Place are 0.6 ft short of the
standard for the DD7 lot type. This is a
1.5%
This is 1.5% of the required 40 foot of
frontage that is needed. Um this
frontage is smaller when compared to the
front edge of lots in the immediate
area. However, the overall lot area is
similar to the to other lots. Um the
remaining lot faces Ridge Road would be
considered DD5 in the MR zone. There is
a condition attached to this plat. The
board of public utilities is asking for
a wider utility easement and the
applicant did mention that BOPU has said
that it's okay. I have not heard that
from BOPU. Um due to the fact that they
require a 10 ft of separation between
the water and sewer line of the and the
easement.
Um, after meeting all review criteria,
staff recommends approval with
conditions
and I stand for questions.
>> Okay, thank you. And I guess for the
record, I should probably note that
Commissioner Trip rejoined the meeting
during the applicant's presentation.
Um,
are there any questions for staff from
the commission?
Uh, Commissioner Leair,
>> Mr. Chair, through you, does that um the
existing building buildings on the east
half the lot or the east portion
um meet what with the proposed
subdivision of the lots meet uh setbacks
and other requirements for that lot
type?
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, yes, it does currently.
And to follow up, and will they continue
to meet setback requirements uh
following the proposed plat?
>> Uh Mr. Chair, through you, yes, they
will. And and for the record, this is a
burnt out building. No one's using it
right now. So, um we'll probably see a
site plan come through for it possibly
if it doesn't go back to residential.
So, I can picture exactly which building
we're talking about here. I I drive by
this building multiple times daily.
Okay. And did I uh I've got a question.
Did I hear correctly that there's a
request to to forego
sidewalk access as part of the street
widening? Did I pick up on that
correctly?
Okay.
And then finally,
if if we don't have BOU
telling us or reporting that that it
the proposal is is acceptable.
Uh
what do we need to do in order to make
sure
that we get that in writing?
>> Mr. share counterway planning
development department. Uh right now
staff is proposing that condition if you
just move forward with the condition
that staff recommends if we get through
or when we get to council either the
condition continues uh through council
or BOPU can provide us something in
writing that says a sat satisfactory and
then we have something but having that
condition would probably be the best
route forward.
Okay, thank you. Any other questions,
comments?
Okay, with that, I'll open this up for
public comment.
Is there any member of the public via
Zoom that wants to comment?
>> Mr. Chair, Brandon does have his hand
raised again.
>> Uh, well, I believe that we we'll give
the applicant an opportunity to respond
to public comment.
Okay. Public comment going once. Public
comment going twice. Public comment is
now closed.
Okay. Commissioner, not commission.
Director Bloom, you look like you want
to say something before we let the
applicant respond to questions.
>> Chair, members of planning commission,
it it Brandon had forwarded me some
information. It looks like he has had
some discussions with board of public
utilities that may have just not
included us to fully loop us in on the
discussion regarding the utilities. So
it looks like there have been
discussions about maintaining a 10-ft
easement and ensuring that they meet the
separation requirements between water
and sewer lines which is 5 ft and that's
an environmental quality rule. So it
appears that there has been some
discussions but we need to make sure
that we work on our communication
processes internally. Um there's more
transition occurring at board of public
utilities right now. So we'll have to
train the next new person that comes in.
>> Okay.
Thank you. And
I guess at this point uh for the
applicant there wasn't any comments from
public to respond to I don't think. So
unless somebody has a quformformational
questions for applicant I'm looking for
a motion from the commission.
>> Mr. Mr. Chair, just a question
follow up on Director Bloom's comment.
So, are we are you suggesting now we not
include the condition that's that's been
discussed before about the water and
sewer easement in our motion?
>> Chair, members of the planning
commission, it wouldn't hurt to leave
that in there. Um, it'll be one that is
we'll just mark it satisfied if if it
is. We'll have to further discussion,
but I just keep it in there for now.
Okay.
Looking for a motion, I believe.
Mr. Chair,
>> I move to approve the Darnell Homesite
second filing preliminary plat advancing
the final plat to the governing body
with conditions. Number one, water and
sewer service line easement need to meet
Board of Public Utilities request for a
wider easement.
Okay, it's been moved. Do I have a
second?
>> Second.
>> Okay,
second and third. Okay, we now have a
motion before the commission.
Any discussion? Any clarification,
questions, amendments,
thoughts?
Seeing none, will staff please call
roll.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Justin Trip.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Thank you. Will staff please read
item F into the record.
>> Item F, PUDC-26-88,
jail ranch zoning map amendment.
>> Okay. Will the applicant please present
your proposal?
>> And Mr. Chair, our applicant is online
again because it is uh Mr. Swain.
>> Mr. Swain.
>> Good evening, chair, members of the
planning commission. Brandon Swain, 3201
Cheyenne Street. Uh we do have um I
believe a newer member on the planning
commission. So, um I think it's
important to to gain some context of
what we're requesting here. A zone
change seems fairly aggressive, but I
think when I'm done explaining the
nature of why we arrived at this, it'll
make sense. Uh so this project is
located in JL Ranch. Um uh pretty neat
development there that's just east of
town just south of Interstate 80. Uh
subdivision started likely 15 years ago
or so. Got built out about halfway. Um
I'm not sure what happened. Perhaps it
was a change in the market or what have
you. Um but about half of the
subdivision remains undeveloped. It's
currently platted but the subdivision
isn't fully built out. At the time it
was established, it was formed as what's
called a plan unit development. Um to
oversimplify it, sometimes uh developers
will propose a product that doesn't
quite meet expectations of what the UDC
will allow. However, at that time, a
plan unit development was available
which allows the developer to propose
some things that exceed standards and
able to receive relief on other
standards. and they call it a plan unit
development because the city will hold
the developer to that agreement in
perpetuity. What's now changed um in
between then and now is the cost of
housing and building has gone up
significantly. The board of public
utilities perhaps three or four years
ago offers a smaller water meter size.
So, if you have a dwelling, it's it's a
modest size home, only two bathrooms,
oftent times this smaller water meter is
a fantastic fit because you still get
adequate water pressure. Both will
perform those calculations in house to
make sure that everything is going to
function properly. The exchange though
and Boo's expectation is that you have
250 ft of turf or less. So, uh someone
has a heart posture towards affordable
housing. they are now purchasing the
remainder of the lots. They're doing
everything they can to try and help make
these products affordable and and I very
much understand that because this is
something that I do with my own
developments. I've used that smaller
water meter uh probably a dozen times by
now. And just to give you context, it's
about a $4,500 savings um per unit that
we can then pass on to the homeowner.
Um, however, again, I'll reiterate
BOPU's expectation is 250 square feet of
turf or less. How the PUB
uh acronym for plan unit development,
how the PUB was formed stated that the
yards are going to be fully solded and
irrigated in the front. So, basically,
we have a conflict between the two
policies and as a matter of procedure
with the planning development
department, which I completely
understand, um, they're going to hold
the current developer to those PU
standards. uh we decided collectively
that the best way to remove the product
out of that would be to reszone to NR2.
Um that way all the future dwellings to
be constructed are in compliance. It's
then going to allow the applicant to
have discretion on how they want to
landscape the front whether it be fully
solded or um zero escape. And we say
zero escape, I don't mean zerocape.
Zerocape meaning natural plants and
they'll still have a tree. the they just
won't have this artificial excuse me not
artificial but um an unnecessary amount
of turf up front. So kind of an
aggressive action to be able to simply
just reduce the turf or have discretion
in doing so. How however uh this was set
by the original developer and the city
is is is just and holding us to the
current PUD. Um, anytime you amend
zoning, you have to mail letters to
property owners within 300 ft as we
nearly reszoning half the subdivision. I
mailed quite a bit of letters. Um, to my
knowledge, I haven't received any
adverse calls. Um, perhaps staff may,
I'm not sure, but again, this is not
changing the nature of what the current
neighborhood is. It's it's simply just
allowing us to adjust the landscaping in
a way that can meet the board of public
utility standards in a way that can
afford us the opportunity to offer these
units to the homeowners at nearly four
to $5,000 less. That being said, I stand
for any questions.
Okay. Thank you, uh, commission. Any
questions for the applicant?
Any anything from commissioners on Zoom?
I do have a quick question. Uh, in
addition to the change in the
landscaping standards for turf,
uh, by virtue of reszoning out of the
PUD, are there any other landscaping
changes or any other landscaping relief
that that this resoning is going to
accomplish?
>> Um, to my knowledge, no. Um because
these are single family dwellings. I
think I think once you get into a
project that necessitates a site plan um
which I believe to be a building that
has three or more attached dwelling
units in it or excuse me three or more
living units in it or some type of
commercial property. Um, but I believe
the through the UDC the enforcement and
expectation is going to be the same on
these as they would any other property,
whether it be planning a development or
the city forester. Um, the the the turf
is really a self-inflicted
expectation that was set long ago when
the development was first proposed
through that PUD. I don't know that it's
ever been a city requirement to have a
certain amount of turf in the in in
front. Anyhow, I hope that answers the
question.
>> Okay, thank you. Will staff, please read
your report into the record.
>> Mr. Chair, members of the commission,
Morgan Dennis, Planning and Development.
This is a zone change for about 6.77
acres or I believe it's 58 parcels uh
located southwest of HR Ranch Road and
Jud Judy Lee Drive and one parcel
southeast of HR Road HR Ranch Road and
Judy Lee Drive. Um most of this land is
currently vacant.
The future land use map designates this
area as mixeduse residential. This
designation primarily supports
highdensity residential development with
a secondary focus on commercial uses
that'd be supportive of the
neighborhood. Surrounding zone uh the
zone itself is obviously JL Ranch PUD.
The surrounding zones are CB LI and HI
zones that are supportive of commercial
and industrial uses isolating NR2 to
this air. So the zone change with the
zone change it'd be isolating NR2 to
this area.
Um this the JL Ranch PUD was adopted in
2006 and amended in 2008 prior to the
adoption of the UDC. Aspects of the PUD
are very similar to the NR2 zone
district uh resulting in minimal impact
on the existing surrounding properties.
The depth of the existing lots would
require the applicants to seek an
administrative adjustment for rear
setbacks.
Um staff has heard from the public
regarding this zone change. One caller
was fine with the zone change and the
another caller would have preferred if
the parcels remain in the jail ranch
PUD. After meeting all review criteria,
staff recommends approval and I stand
for questions.
Any
questions of staff from the commission?
Uh, Commissioner Leair,
>> Mr. Chair, through you. I
maybe I missed it in the comments, but
why why is that uh lot 24 on the east
side and then lot 10 up there, the
northeast corner excluded from the
change? Is there a particular reason?
>> Mr. Chair, uh, through you Connorway
Planning Development Department. So, lot
24 is currently under different
ownership.
So, I believe that lot's already been
sold. So, um can't really include that
in this zone change from the applicant
because they don't own the lot. They'd
have to get basically that lot owner to
agree to that. And then lot 10 up in the
corner, lot 10 and actually nine, uh are
city-owned. Um it's a small little kind
of park area up there that the city
owns. So, that's why those are not
included.
Um, and actually lot 9 and 10 is
developed uh with with the park. So,
it's a small park that is developed out
there. Um, but that's the reason those
aren't included. They're just they're
not under ownership of the applicant who
is requesting.
Mr. Chair, you it does look kind of
funny if you go out there and see this
park playground clear up there in the
corner way from where anybody lives. And
it's the other thing that didn't come up
I think in the discussion but is in the
report is this discussion about the
4-foot fence requirement and I from my
days in the board of adjustment we had
quite a contentious variance dis uh
issue on one of those lots. It's already
developed because the owner uh changed
some fences to more than 4 foot.
Okay. Um any other questions of staff?
I've got a question as we're prop as
we're evaluating this even though
there's a nice break there at Judy Lee
Drive.
um other than
the landscaping issue and then I believe
there is mentioned that there would
there's not adequate room for a rear
setback under the NR2 zone for these
lots.
Would the other dwellings that that have
already been developed in this project
generally fit the the proposed zoning?
Mr. Chair, through you. Yes. So, this
whole neighborhood for the most part,
except for the ones that don't have
alley access, everything is alley
loaded. Um, there's no front loading.
Again, there are some select parcels
that have to be frontloaded. As you can
see, even the ones that they're
proposing to reszone lots 1, 2, 3, and
four on the very south of Alex Ranch
will probably need some administrative
relief to frontloading because there is
no alley. So
there are some lots within the
neighborhood that have to be frontloaded
because there is no alley access, but
generally I would say that this whole
neighborhood could be NR2.
And and secondly, did I correctly
understand though that that with the
reszoning,
every time
somebody wants to build a house in one
of these existing lots, they're going to
have to get relief from the setback
requirement under the zone we're about
to Mr. Chair, through you. So what we
would probably look at as staff is doing
just a blanket administrative adjustment
to all the lots for rear setback to
allow them to develop similar to what
exists. Staff understands that these are
pre-existing lots and understands why
the applicant is requesting this change.
Staff does prefer this change than the
current PUD. Um but we could do a
blanket administrative adjun
administrative adjustment for all rear
setbacks. So, it's not every time a
building permit comes in, they have to
tack on the administrative adjustment.
>> And to clarify, that doesn't need to
come before the planning commission.
>> Mr. Chair, no, it does not. Um, this is
something that staff with, we've done it
with plats. We bring it up at planning
commission and at council that this is
something that would need to come back
to staff for administrative review for
the rear setback portion or some setback
reduction based on the project. Um, and
we bring that up front as long as
planning commission and council are good
with that. As the project move moves
forward, then we kind of take the
approvals as you're okay with staff also
kind of doing the administrative
approval.
Okay. Thank you.
Um, I guess I'll we heard about uh from
the public. I will open this up for
public comment.
There any members of the public that
wish to address this before the
commission?
Public comment going once, going twice.
Public comment is now closed.
Recognizing that two comments were read
into the record earlier,
I am now looking for a motion from the
commission.
Sher Hibbon.
>> Yes. I move to uh approve the reszoning
of lots 1-23
11-15
block five lots 1-23
25-32
block 6 lots 1-4
block 7 JL Ranch and lot 34
block JL Ranch ranch
5 or V
to from GL Ranch PUD to NR
to neighborhood residential medium
density as shown in the attached zone
change map noting that the project meets
the review criteria for approval.
>> Okay, thank you. Before we get a second,
uh, can we understand that anytime you
referred to like lot 1-23 that you
referring to lots 1 through 23
>> or is that your intent?
>> Yes, that's my intent.
>> Okay. So, with that clarification, do we
have a second?
Commissioner Leair,
>> Mr. Chair, before a second. I'm thinking
there's got to be a number missing in
there. You see where it says on the
second line, lot 34, and then it just
says block. Seems to me like there must
be a block number that's not in the
motion.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Yeah, it's
supposed to be block two,
lot 34, block two,
jail ranch v.
Um, I think I need a second before I can
ask for an amendment, unless the mover
would like to restate his motion.
>> Yes.
Would you like to try again? Yes. Would
you like to I I believe that this is
referring it. Looking at the map, it
looks to me like this refers to block 2,
lot 34.
And and can I before we get into trying
to restate our motion to clarify it,
there's a reference to JL Ranch B. Is
there a particular reason for this?
>> Is you want
>> is that a typo or is that something Mr.
Chair threw you? um that portion of Jail
Ranch was subdivided. Uh they changed
the lots.
So that's just instead of it being Jail
Ranch first filing, it's fifth filing.
But they I think they just called it
Jail Ranch V for five. But
>> okay,
>> it's however they name the plat.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Please do
go forth.
>> I move to approve the reasonzoning of
lots 1 through 23,
11- 15. Block five, lots 1- 23,
25- 32. Block six, lots 1 through 4.
Block seven, JL Ranch and lot 34.
Block two,
JL Ranch
V
2 from JL Ranch PUD to NR2
neighborhood residential medium density
as shown in the attached zone change
map. Noting that project meets the
review criteria for approval.
>> Okay, thank you. Do I have a second?
>> Second.
>> Okay, thank you.
Uh comments, questions, proposed
amendments,
discussion from the commission?
Anything from the commissioners online?
Hearing none, will staff please call
roll.
Justin Trip.
>> Hi.
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Tony Lair.
>> Hi.
>> Bob.
>> Mathia.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair. That motion passes.
Okay. Thank you.
Other business or staff announcements?
and chair, members of the planning
commission. Uh first of all, just like
to do a couple of introductions here for
our new member, uh Justin Trip. Um
first, we'll start with staff real
quick. I'm Charles Bloom, planning and
development director. I've been here
since fall of 2018. I I think I held the
record for the longest
executive planning and development
director since like the late 1990s here
for the city of Cheyenne. I don't know
if that's just an award or just if it's
just a bad thought on my end. Um, with
me here today we have um Connor White
and I'll let him introduce himself and
then I'll pull Aaron to the stand
and she looks comfortable.
So, I'm Connor White. I'm a planner 2
with the planning and development
department. I've been with the city be
going on seven years this October.
uh originally from Buffalo, New York, so
east coast, but I did get my masters at
Utah State University, so I have been to
the west. I do have family in Utah, so
not unfamiliar with out here, but never
actually lived or really been to
Cheyenne until I moved here. So that was
uh different, but um yeah, been here
going on seven. So,
>> okay.
>> Hi. Um, I'm Morgan Dennis. I'm the
planner one department. I've been here
since August of 2025.
Um, I'm originally from OK a small town
in Oklahoma um called Morrison. Um,
went to school at the University of
Oklahoma. Um, I do have family out here.
I've been to Wyoming a number of times
and I'm really excited to be out here.
>> While Jazelle's making her way up, I I'm
I've was in Laramie, Wyoming for 13
years prior to being out here. Moved to
Cheyenne in 2005. grew up in eastern
Washington and spent about a decade in
the Boulder and Arvvada area and a
little bit of time in Arkansas. Um,
proud Colorado Buffalo graduate.
>> I'm Jesselle Pacheco and I've lived in
Cheyenne my whole life. Um, I am the
office manager for the planning and
development as well as the MO and I
pretty much keep everybody in line. So,
Good afternoon. I'm Erin Gates. I'm a
staff engineer in the engineering
department. Spent uh 20 plus years on
the consulting side and then joined the
city just over two years ago.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Announcements.
>> Uh Mr. Chair, we will have well sure
you're aware with the postponement, we
will have our midmon and as director
Bloom mentioned, we will have two text
amendments. Um that one being the
postponed one from tonight and then
carports.
Uh carports was basically requested by a
council member for us to bring that
forward. The gist of it, just as a heads
up, is looking at allowing them to be on
front driveways, so in the front of your
house. Um,
they currently aren't allowed. Uh,
>> oh,
>> correct. They currently are not allowed.
So, anybody who has a carport in their
front driveway, it's probably illegal.
Um, and a zoning violation.
They are considered accessory buildings.
They need to meet accessory building
setbacks currently. Basically, this text
amendment removes them from being
considered accessory buildings and
allows properties to have a carport. Um,
and it can be in your front on the front
driveway. This is something that staff
gets questions and comments and calls
about all the time. Um, so if this is
the community's desire to have carports
on your front driveway and it is
council's and planning commission's
desire to also allow them,
then we can go forward with that and
allow them. Um, so that's the other text
amendment.
Uh we do have
the RFP out for plan Cheyenne for the
future land use uh basically our
comprehensive plan update. So the RFP is
out. So that's something where we'll be
looking at getting a consultant and
moving that process forward to get that
whole plan updated which you will
eventually see because it does have to
come before you. But that's probably a
year out I'm guessing Charles for that.
So um but feel free to be involved when
the consultants do uh start putting out
either surveys or if there's public
meetings, open houses, things like that.
Please feel free to be involved. You are
community members. We're always going to
be looking for input. Um especially with
this project because it is our guiding
document for the growth and development
of Cheyenne.
Uh just as a reminder, June's planning
commission um and please let me know
ahead of time if you won't be here. It's
going to be a very long agenda. Um right
now I am anticipating anywhere of
upwards of 12 items on that agenda
and we'll see how controversial some of
them are. Um
so that will be a long agenda. Expect a
long night that evening. Uh, but please
try to be here if you can be. Um, if you
can't, please just let me know. Um,
what else? I don't know if you have
anything else question about the plan
Cheyenne document. Is there any part of
that that comes to us before essentially
the final draft formally or is it just
if we go out and find activities in the
city
>> and chair members of the planning
commission great question um we really
hope to keep you all involved in this as
well right now the RFP is out on the
streets we've had a lot of interest in
people responding to this a lot of
interest which is pretty exciting we
hope to have a contract executed um by
July 1st and that's the to- go date. Um
we will be doing interviews of
consultants coming up in the near
future. Um so if any of the planning
commission members would like to be on
that interview committee, that panel,
we'd be more than happy to to host you.
Um you'd probably have to read about
probably about six or seven RFPs that
we'll probably weed out that are about
the top. Um they're about 20 pages long
to look at their approach. Um, so if
you're interested in that, feel free to
uh drop either Connor or myself or any
of our planning staff a line and we'll
get you in line for that. Uh, we don't
exactly know what the consultants are
proposing when it comes to public
engagement. However, we have asked that
they engage the planning commission on
multiple levels. Number one, kind of at
the early level and also as it evolves.
Um, we'll also be creating a steering
committee, but of course we don't know
what this looks like yet because we're
going to wait for some advice from the
consultants, but we'll have a steering
committee that will help uh guide this
as well. So, long story short, there
will be opportunities for involvement.
>> Can you please send out email to all the
members of the planning commission for
that we can respond to if we have a
desire to participate in the interview
process?
>> Yes. And the one item we wanted to
mention was just really quick if you
could just let the new member know who
you are and who you represent. I think
that'd be very valuable. And I'm sure if
he did the exact same that'd be good,
too.
>> Um, quickly, what do you mean by who we
represent?
>> Or not who you represent, like your
Sorry, I should I should say your
background, your you know, what
expertise you lend to the commission.
Well, I guess I'll start that. I'm Boyd
Wiggum. Um,
I grew up in Larmy County. I'm an
attorney, solo attorney here in town.
Uh, before I took a walk on the dark
side and went to law school, I was
studying planning in graduate school.
I'm still trying to figure out how I
took that career de detour.
Commissioner Leairard.
>> Yeah, my name is Tony Leard and I'm a
engineer. Worked 34 years for white dot.
Um, ended up in Cheyenne in 1973. My dad
was a Air Force guy that ended his
career here and uh, I was 12 years old
and I've lived in Wyoming ever since.
Spent some time in Laramie, Rock
Springs, and mostly Cheyenne.
I'm Bob Mati and uh I've gotten had a
degree in accounting and I couldn't
nobody could read my numbers so I got a
degree in economics where it didn't
matter so much
but I ended up in the foreign service
where I spent about 35 years and then I
spent 10 years working as a downtown
developer in the city of South Bend and
then I retired and came here because I
grandkids here.
>> Hi everybody. My name's uh Daryl. I uh
I'm a retired law man. I was in law
enforcement for 35 years and um the last
four years as Richard can tell you. I
did I think helped Cheyenne police do
crashes and write parking tickets was
was not fun compared to what I used to
do. But anyway, um I brought the wife
here about 10 years ago after I retired
um on the West Coast and uh she now just
now celebrated 10 years cancer-free. So,
we're happy to be here.
Commissioner Connor,
Megan,
is Amy still on?
Amy,
hello. I'm here. Um, Amy Hernandez, born
and raised in Cheyenne. Um, I've been in
the banking, mortgage,
real estate industry for 20 plus years.
Currently a title examiner at Flying S
Title and Escrow. Um, very active in the
community on I just finished a six-year
board position with the Cheyenne Depot
Museum. Um, active with Santa Club and
Wyoming Independent Citizens um,
Coalition.
Um, and have three kids, three grown
kids. I have two grandb babies that
should be coming before the end of the
year. So, excited about that.
>> And would you please introduce yourself?
>> Thank you for all the kind introductions
there. My name is Justin Trip. So, I
appreciate the mayor and the council
putting me on the planning commission
with you. I look forward to serving on
this commission. My background I I born
and raised in Michigan, join enlisted in
the US Navy. So I spent several years
there stationed Pearl Harbor, San Diego,
back to Detroit for three years military
recruiting. I've got my masters in human
resource and also a bachelor's in
business management. Uh we've been in
Cheyenne since 2017. So it was a fair
compromise. Uh my wife's from
California. I'm from Michigan. So it's
literally fair compromise. 1,200 miles
to both parents doorsteps. So there you
go. So great deal there. So we're
raising a family here. We love this
community. So I look forward to working
with you guys on this. I also volunteer
with the Veterans of Foreign Wars and uh
my church uh Board of Education.
>> Uh
where do you work?
>> Oh, so I do human resources for a
living. I work at Meridian uh Trust
Federal Credit Union as a human resource
manager.
Okay. And with that, I'm looking for Oh,
one more announcement. Sorry, Mr. Chair.
Through you. I I had another item. I'm
not sure this is the appropriate time to
bring it up, but I I think we should
address something maybe or consider
changes about I'm still troubled by this
one particular vote and uh issue that
came up at the last meeting. We were
trying to change the land use map and we
decided I think it's my recollection
that state statute said the majority of
the commission had to vote in order to
make that change. Our bylaw said the
commit the chairman doesn't vote except
in the case of a tai. Um, and then I
gathered that maybe I don't know, maybe
I lost something here, but maybe that's
the only type of work we do or the only
type of recommendation we make that has
to be approved by a majority of the
board, not just a majority of the board
members present.
>> Yeah.
>> Or voting. Um, but it bothers me a bit
and I think if it's a bylaw issue, I
want I'd be curious. Is it worthwhile to
try to change those bylaws? maybe to let
the chairman vote in the cases of
changing that master plan land use map
type thing.
>> Um Mr. Chair through you. So I actually
have looked at the bylaws and have a
draft
not specifically with that with other
changes to the bylaws because I was also
working on board of adjustments bylaws
which I still have yet to get changed
which desperately need to be changed.
Those ones haven't been changed since
like 1982.
uh whereas at least planning commission
I think were updated
2009ish
uh which is I think around the time when
the city county split so we had to draft
bylaws then um so staff could look at
the bylaws I do already have a draft
because I would actually one of the
changes that I was looking at that would
be more conforming with how all of our
all of our other
boards commissions
city council everything works is staff
goes through the item first and then the
applicant, not the applicant before
staff. Um, planning commission is the
only place I've seen that done. Uh,
where the applicant actually goes before
staff on items. So, that was a change
that I was looking at and then just kind
of updating things to reference how the
commission is actually run today rather
than 2008. Uh, so that is something that
we could look at and talk to the city
attorney to see how we can make that
change. Maybe it is if it's in the case
of a
land, the chair does get to vote whether
there's a tie or not. Um because it's
state statute references a majority of
the commission. It doesn't say the chair
doesn't get to vote unless there's a
tie. That's just the bylaws. So maybe we
can have a section when it comes to
plans where it follows state statute
would meaning the chair gets to vote on
plans so that the chair doesn't have we
don't have to worry about a tie
situation for the chair to vote. The
chair can vote. Um so that is something
I can look into something that we could
try to move forward. I don't know how
quickly that can be. Um, but that is if
planning commission is looking for staff
to do that and wants to direct staff,
then I'd say we could take a look at the
bylaws and maybe get some bylaws updated
uh maybe sometime this year.
>> It would be good to eliminate a
conflict.
>> Mr. chair. I think I would agree and I
think our attorney or city attorneys uh
would also agree cuz having the
discussions with them about how that
vote went uh they also had to look into
it and they they did end up confirming
that technically state statute
does say you need a majority but then
yes the bylaws are conflicting and say
the chair doesn't get to vote. Um so you
kind of have to use both in that case
but
it it does cause that issue. Um so it
would be good to update the bylaws and
remove that issue from future uh future
votes. So
chair may planning commission final
comment. Um there's a question during
the meeting about the status of the
roads and their levels
uh in Harmony Valley Grand Harmony which
is the street that goes uh past Triumph
up the eastern up the eastern side that
is a minor collector street. So it's
designed to be a large thoroughfare that
would have significant volumes of
traffic. York uh connecting the crib is
also a minor collector as well. So those
are uh more than local streets.
Okay, with that I'm looking for a motion
to adjurnn unless somebody else has
something they want to say.
>> I make a motion.
>> It's been moved. Get a motion to
adjurnn. So we are adjourned.